//array for each of the different difficulty levels stored below

const easyQuestions = [{
    question: "What is the name of Harry Potter's Owl?",
    answers: [ 
        {text: "Hermes", },
        {text: "Scabbers"},
        {text: "Fawkes"},
        {text: "Hedwig"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Hedwig"
},
{
    question: "What was Lily Potter's surname before she married James Potter?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Evans"},
        {text: "Smith"},
        {text: "Peters"},
        {text: "Cullen"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Evans"
},
{
    question: "Who kills Albus Dumbledore?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Draco Malfoy"},
        {text: "Severus Snape"},
        {text: "Voldemort"},
        {text: "Bellatrix Lestrange"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Severus Snape"
},
{
    question: "What spell put Neville Longbottom's parents in the long term ward of St. Mungos?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Avada Kedavra"},
        {text: "Imperious Curse"},
        {text: "Crucio Curse"},
        {text: "Expulso"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Crucio Curse"
},
{
    question: "What animal did Hermione Granger turn into when she drank Polyjuice Potion?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Owl"},
        {text: "Dog"},
        {text: "Cat"},
        {text: "Rat"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Cat"
},
{
    question: "Who put Harry Potter's name in the Goblet of Fire?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Igor Karkoroff "},
        {text: "Mad Eye Moody"},
        {text: "Severus Snape"},
        {text: "Barty Crouch JR"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Barty Crouch JR"
},
{
    question: "What Hogwarts house was Harry Potter nearly sorted into?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Ravenclaw"},
        {text: "Slytherin"},
        {text: "Gryffindor"},
        {text: "Hufflepuff"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Slytherin"
},
{
    question: "What is the name of the Cerebeus that guards the trapdoor to the philosopher's stone?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Sooty"},
        {text: "Smiley"},
        {text: "Squishy"},
        {text: "Fluffy"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Fluffy"
},
{
    question: "How do you close the Marauder's Map?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Mischief Managed"},
        {text: "Mischievo Completo"},
        {text: "Mischief No Good"},
        {text: "Mischief done"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Mischief Managed"
},
{
    question: "What plant did Harry Potter eat in the second task of the Goblet of Fire?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Fluxweed"},
        {text: "Gillyweed"},
        {text: "Asphodel"},
        {text: "Mandrake"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Gillyweed"
},
{
    question: "What was prongs' real name?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Sirius Black"},
        {text: "Peter Pettigrew"},
        {text: "Remus Lupin"},
        {text: "James Potter"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "James Potter"
},
{
    question: "How does Harry Potter catch his first snitch?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Hand"},
        {text: "Mouth"},
        {text: "He doesn't catch it"},
        {text: "A spell"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Mouth"
},
{
    question: "Who hexed Harry Potter's broom in his first quidditch game ever?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Severus Snape"},
        {text: "Voldemort"},
        {text: "Quirinus Quirrell"},
        {text: "Peter Pettigrew"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Quirinus Quirrell"
},
{
    question: "What animal can you speak to and undestand as a parselmouth?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Snakes"},
        {text: "Dragons"},
        {text: "Spiders"},
        {text: "Lizards"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Snakes"
},
{
    question: "What magical creature pulls the carriages to Hogwarts?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Unicorns"},
        {text: "Thestrals"},
        {text: "Hippogriffs"},
        {text: "Werewolves"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Thestrals"
},
{
    question: "What charm illuminates the tip of the caster's wand?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Lumos"},
        {text: "Lumen"},
        {text: "Lumiere"},
        {text: "Lux"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Lumos"
},
{
    question: "What is Ron Weasley's pet rat's name?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Pig"},
        {text: "Scabbers"},
        {text: "Fang"},
        {text: "Dobby"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Scabbers"
},
{
    question: "What Quidditch position does Harry Potter play?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Keeper"},
        {text: "Chaser"},
        {text: "Beater"},
        {text: "Seeker"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Seeker"
},
{
    question: "Who is the Bulgarian Quidditch team's seeker?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Viktor Krum"},
        {text: "Aidan Lynch"},
        {text: "Galvin Gudgeon"},
        {text: "Gwenog Jones"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Viktor Krum"
},
{
    question: "Who tells Harry Potter that he's a wizard?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Albus Dumbledore"},
        {text: "Minerva McGonagall"},
        {text: "Hagrid"},
        {text: "Severus Snape"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Hagrid"
},
{
    question: "What is Hermione Granger's half kneazle's name?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Crookshanks"},
        {text: "Trevor"},
        {text: "Pig"},
        {text: "Scabbers"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Crookshanks"
},
{
    question: "Who gifts Harry Potter his Firebolt broom?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Albus Dumbledore"},
        {text: "Minerva McGonagall"},
        {text: "Oliver Wood"},
        {text: "Sirius Black"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Sirius Black"
},
{
    question: "Who was Severus Snape in love with?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Lily Potter"},
        {text: "Petunia Dursley"},
        {text: "Hestia Jones"},
        {text: "Amelia Bones"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Lily Potter"
},
{
    question: "From which platform at King's Cross does the Hogwarts Express depart?",
    answers: [
        {text: "9 and 3 quarters"},
        {text: "10 and a half"},
        {text: "9"},
        {text: "10 and 4 thirds"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "9 and 3 quarters"
},
{
    question: "What shape is Harry Potter's scar on his forehead?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Star"},
        {text: "Wand"},
        {text: "Lightening bolt"},
        {text: "Cauldron"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Lightening bolt"
},
{
    question: "On a quidditch pitch, how many goal posts are there in total?",
    answers: [
        {text: "3"},
        {text: "6"},
        {text: "4"},
        {text: "8"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "6"
},
{
    question: "What does Hagrid name his baby dragon?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Norbert"},
        {text: "Fluffy"},
        {text: "Fang"},
        {text: "Pig"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Norbert"
},
{
    question: "What does Hagrid gift Harry Potter in Diagon Alley on their first trip?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Toad"},
        {text: "Eagle"},
        {text: "Owl"},
        {text: "Kneazle"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Owl"
},
{
    question: "Who runs the Gringotts Wizarding bank in Diagon Alley?",
    answers: [
        {text: "House Elves"},
        {text: "Goblins"},
        {text: "Centaurs"},
        {text: "Leprachauns"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Goblins"
},
{
    question: "What is Flich's pet cat's name?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Mrs. Norris"},
        {text: "Mrs. Figg"},
        {text: "Mrs. Weasley"},
        {text: "Mrs. Polkiess"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Mrs. Norris"
}
];

const mediumQuestions = [{
    question: "What is Fleur Delacour's sister's name?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Brigitte"},
        {text: "Gabrielle"},
        {text: "Fayette"},
        {text: "Esme"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Gabrielle"
},
{
    question: "What is the name of Ginny Weasley's Pygmy Puff?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Hugo"},
        {text: "Barry"},
        {text: "Arnold"},
        {text: "Richard"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Arnold"
},
{
    question: "What are Neville Longbottom's parent's names?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Frank & Alice"},
        {text: "Arnie & Louise"},
        {text: "Mike & Jane"},
        {text: "James & Dot"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Frank & Alice"
},
{
    question: "What house was Sirius Black sorted into?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Slytherin"},
        {text: "Ravenclaw"},
        {text: "Gryffindor"},
        {text: "Hufflepuff"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Gryffindor"
},
{
    question: "What kind of dragon did Harry Potter face in the First Task?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Hungarian Horntail"},
        {text: "Chinese Fireball"},
        {text: "Welsh Green"},
        {text: "Swedish Short Snout"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Hungarian Horntail"
},
{
    question: "What does Prof. Lupin offer Harry Potter after the dementor attack on the train?",
    answers: [
        {text: "A potion"},
        {text: "Pumpkin Juice"},
        {text: "Treacle Tart"},
        {text: "Chocolate"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Chocolate"
},
{
    question: "What is the name of Hagrid's giant half brother?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Goliath"},
        {text: "Cyclops"},
        {text: "Fridwulfa"},
        {text: "Grawp"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Grawp"
},
{
    question: "Who tells Harry Potter that he's a horcrux?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Severus Snape"},
        {text: "Albus Dumbledore"},
        {text: "Minerva McGonagall"},
        {text: "Sirius Black"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Albus Dumbledore"
},
{
    question: "What is the name of Hagrid's giant pet spider?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Fang"},
        {text: "Buckbeak"},
        {text: "Norbert"},
        {text: "Aragog"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Aragog"
},
{
    question: "What is Harry Potter's date of birth?",
    answers: [
        {text: "31st July 1980"},
        {text: "30th July 1980"},
        {text: "31st June 1981"},
        {text: "30th July 1981"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "31st July 1980"
},
{
    question: "Who hosts the radio show Potterwatch?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Fred & George Weasley"},
        {text: "Dean Thomas"},
        {text: "Seamus Finnegan"},
        {text: "Lee Jordan"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Lee Jordan"
},
{
    question: "Where does Dudley Dursley go to school?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Smeltings"},
        {text: "St. Brutus"},
        {text: "Hogwarts"},
        {text: "Wools"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Smeltings"
},
{
    question: "How fast can a firebolt reach?",
    answers: [
        {text: "140mph"},
        {text: "150mph"},
        {text: "160mph"},
        {text: "170mph"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "150mph"
},
{
    question: "What is Ron Weasley's Patronus?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Jack Russell Terrier"},
        {text: "Labrador"},
        {text: "Collie"},
        {text: "Greyhound"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Jack Russell Terrier"
},
{
    question: "What is the name of the centaur who became a divination teacher in Harry Potter's 6th year",
    answers: [
        {text: "Magorian"},
        {text: "Bane"},
        {text: "Ronan"},
        {text: "Firenze"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Firenze"
},
{
    question: "What portkey took Harry Potter to the Quidditch World Cup?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Old rubber tyre"},
        {text: "Old boot"},
        {text: "Punctured football"},
        {text: "Empty drink can"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Old boot"
},
{
    question: "How did Moaning Myrtle die?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Mountain troll"},
        {text: "Killing Curse"},
        {text: "Basilisk"},
        {text: "Acromantula"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Basilisk"
},
{
    question: "What potion does Harry Potter pretend to gove Ron Weasley during a Quidditch match?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Draught of Peace"},
        {text: "Amortentia"},
        {text: "Pepperup"},
        {text: "Felix Felicis"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Felix Felicis"
},
{
    question: "What does Lavender Brown call Ron Weasley when they are dating?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Ronnikens"},
        {text: "Won-Won"},
        {text: "Ronnie"},
        {text: "Ron-Won"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Won-Won"
},
{
    question: "What is Reeter Skeeter's animagus form?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Water Beetle"},
        {text: "Dung Beetle"},
        {text: "Beetle"},
        {text: "Stag Beetle"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Beetle"
},
{
    question: "Where can a bezoar be found?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Goat's stomach"},
        {text: "Cow's stomach"},
        {text: "Snake's stomach"},
        {text: "Wolf's stomach"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Goat's stomach"
},
{
    question: "What other witch/wizard could the prophecy have been about?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Dean Thomas"},
        {text: "Luna Lovegood"},
        {text: "Susan Bones"},
        {text: "Neville Longbottom"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Neville Longbottom"
},
{
    question: "Who is the Half-Blood Prince?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Eileen Prince"},
        {text: "Severus Snape"},
        {text: "Lucious Malfoy"},
        {text: "Tom Riddle"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Severus Snape"
},
{
    question: "Who became a professional Quidditch player?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Harry Potter"},
        {text: "Ron Weasley"},
        {text: "Ginny Weasley"},
        {text: "Charlie Weasley"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Ginny Weasley"
},
{
    question: "What position did James Potter play for his Quidditch House team?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Seeker"},
        {text: "Chaser"},
        {text: "Keeper"},
        {text: "Beater"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Chaser"
},
{
    question: "At what number house does Vernon and Petunia Dursley live?",
    answers: [
        {text: "4"},
        {text: "5"},
        {text: "6"},
        {text: "7"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "4"
},
{
    question: "What is Hermione Granger's parent's profession?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Doctors"},
        {text: "Hygienists"},
        {text: "Nurses"},
        {text: "Dentists"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Dentists"
},
{
    question: "How old was Tom Riddle when he first opened the Chamber of Secrets?",
    answers: [
        {text: "15"},
        {text: "16"},
        {text: "17"},
        {text: "18"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "16"
},
{
    question: "In what year did Harry Potter go on a date with Cho Chang?",
    answers: [
        {text: "4th year"},
        {text: "5th year"},
        {text: "6th year"},
        {text: "7th year"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "5th year"
},
{
    question: "What spell is a full body bind?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Alohomora"},
        {text: "Expecto Patronum"},
        {text: "Lumos"},
        {text: "Petrificus Totalus"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Petrificus Totalus"
},
{
    question: "Who teaches astronomy at Hogwarts?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Charity Burbage"},
        {text: "Aurora Sinistra"},
        {text: "Alecto Carrow"},
        {text: "Sybill Trelawney"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Aurora Sinistra"
}
];

const hardQuestions = [{
    question: "What does Viktor Krum's wand contain?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Dragon Heartstring"},
        {text: "Thestral Hair"},
        {text: "Phoenix Feather"},
        {text: "Unicorn Hair"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Dragon Heartstring"
},
{
    question: "Who does Draco Malfoy marry in the epilogue?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Pansy Parkinson"},
        {text: "Astoria Greengrass"},
        {text: "Georgina Goyle"},
        {text: "Millicent Bulstrode"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Astoria Greengrass"
},
{
    question: "What year was Moaning Myrtle killed in?",
    answers: [
        {text: "1940"},
        {text: "1948"},
        {text: "1943"},
        {text: "1945"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "1943"
},
{
    question: "What are Severus Snapes' parent's names?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Theo & Ethel"},
        {text: "Toby & Ellen"},
        {text: "Tom & Elaina"},
        {text: "Tobias & Eileen"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Tobias & Eileen"
},
{
    question: "What does Harry Potter smell when he sniffs Amortentia",
    answers: [
        {text: "Freshly Mown Grass"},
        {text: "Treacle Tart"},
        {text: "New Parchment"},
        {text: "Fresh Air"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Treacle Tart"
},
{
    question: "What is Hermione Granger's patronus?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Otter"},
        {text: "Labrador"},
        {text: "Swan"},
        {text: "Horse"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Otter"
},
{
    question: "Who told Harry Potter he had to die to get rid of the horcrux?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Albus Dumbledore"},
        {text: "Sirius Black"},
        {text: "Minerva McGonagall"},
        {text: "Severus Snape"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Severus Snape"
},
{
    question: "On what day are Fred & George Weasley born?",
    answers: [
        {text: "April 2nd"},
        {text: "April 31st"},
        {text: "April 15th"},
        {text: "April 1st"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "April 1st"
},
{
    question: "What house was Tonks sorted into?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Hufflepuff"},
        {text: "Gryffindor"},
        {text: "Slytherin"},
        {text: "Ravenclaw"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Hufflepuff"
},
{
    question: "How many presents did Dudley Dursley get on his 11th birthday?",
    answers: [
        {text: "35"},
        {text: "36"},
        {text: "37"},
        {text: "38"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "36"
},
{
    question: "How is Bellatrix Lestrange related to Draco Malfoy?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Aunt"},
        {text: "Cousin"},
        {text: "Aunt in Law"},
        {text: "2nd Cousin"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Aunt"
},
{
    question: "How many staircases are there in Hogwarts?",
    answers: [
        {text: "140"},
        {text: "141"},
        {text: "142"},
        {text: "143"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "142"
},
{
    question: "What is Albus Dumbledore's scar on his knee a map of?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Hogsmeade"},
        {text: "Diagon Alley"},
        {text: "Hogwarts"},
        {text: "London Underground"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "London Underground"
},
{
    question: "What numbers are dialled to activate the entrance to the Ministry of Magic?",
    answers: [
        {text: "26442"},
        {text: "62442"},
        {text: "24664"},
        {text: "64226"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "62442"
},
{
    question: "Monkswood and wolfsbane are the same plant, also known as?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Aconite"},
        {text: "Fluxweed"},
        {text: "Gillyweed"},
        {text: "knotgrass"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Aconite"
},
{
    question: "Where does Vernon Dursley work?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Surrey Drills"},
        {text: "Grunnings"},
        {text: "Smeltings"},
        {text: "Brutus"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Grunnings"
},
{
    question: "What colour did Hermione Granger turn the Weasley's crab apple tree for Harry Potter's 17th birthday?",
    answers: [
        {text: "red & gold"},
        {text: "red"},
        {text: "gold"},
        {text: "red & yellow"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "gold"
},
{
    question: "What does Albus Dumbledore tell Harry Potter he sees in the Mirror of Erised?",
    answers: [
        {text: "His sister"},
        {text: "His family"},
        {text: "His brother"},
        {text: "Socks"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Socks"
},
{
    question: "What is Voldemort's mother's name?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Merope Riddle"},
        {text: "Millicent Gaunt"},
        {text: "Merope Gaunt"},
        {text: "Millicient Merope"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Merope Riddle"
},
{
    question: "What was the name of the caretaker of the Riddle House in the Goblet of Fire?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Francis Burns"},
        {text: "Frank Bryce"},
        {text: "Barry Fitz"},
        {text: "Brian Fuller"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Frank Bryce"
},
{
    question: "What is the name of the orphanage Tom Riddle was left at?",
    answers: [
        {text: "St. Brutus"},
        {text: "Smeltings"},
        {text: "Wools"},
        {text: "Catchpole"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Wools"
},
{
    question: "What is the name of Aragog's wife?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Mosag"},
        {text: "Grawp"},
        {text: "Gasog"},
        {text: "Mogas"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Mosag"
},
{
    question: "What wood is Lily Potter's wand made of?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Birch"},
        {text: "Ash"},
        {text: "Cherry"},
        {text: "Willow"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Willow"
},
{
    question: "How old was Nicholas Flamel when the Philosopher's stone destroyed?",
    answers: [
        {text: "663"},
        {text: "664"},
        {text: "665"},
        {text: "667"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "665"
},
{
    question: "How many possible Quidditch fouls are there?",
    answers: [
        {text: "900"},
        {text: "800"},
        {text: "700"},
        {text: "600"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "700"
},
{
    question: "In the Department of Mysteries, what row holds the prophecy about Harry Potter and Voldemort?",
    answers: [
        {text: "67"},
        {text: "77"},
        {text: "87"},
        {text: "97"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "97"
},
{
    question: "In the Quidditch world cup, which Irish chaser scored the first goal?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Mullet"},
        {text: "Troy"},
        {text: "Moran"},
        {text: "Lynch"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Troy"
},
{
    question: "What is the name of the Apparition instructor who comes to Hogwarts in Harry Potter's 6th year?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Wilkie Twycross"},
        {text: "Mafalda Hopkirk"},
        {text: "Reginald Cattermole"},
        {text: "Bertha Jorkins"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Wilkie Twycross"
},
{
    question: "What is the name of Hepzibah Smith's house elf?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Winky"},
        {text: "Pokey"},
        {text: "Hokey"},
        {text: "Wokey"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Hokey"
},
{
    question: "What is Fred Weasley's chosen code name on Potterwatch?",
    answers: [
        {text: "Rodent"},
        {text: "Rapier"},
        {text: "River"},
        {text: "Royal"}
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Rapier"
}
];